Kaiju No. 8.
怪兽8号
To think that a kaiju had snuck into the Defense Force!
没想到怪兽竟然混进了防卫队里
And a Daikaiju class at that.
而且还是大怪兽级的怪兽
We must deal with this right away.
我们得尽快处理这件事
Will we be releasing this to the press?
要通知媒体吗？
We should avoid it, as we did with No. 9.
最好像9号那次压下来吧
Some countries have begun transplanting kaiju tissues on human bodies.
听说有国家已经开始 研究把怪兽组织移植到人体
They would cause a big fuss.
他们可不会闷不作声
We must exterminate it quietly and use the materials for weapons.
应该立即秘密处决然后应用到兵器上
Before that,
在此之前
should we not consider using it as a living weapon?
不先考虑当成生物兵器来运用吗？
There's no use debating hypotheticals.
光是纸上谈兵没有用
First, we must contain the kaiju.
处置方式等收容之后再说吧
I order the Third Division
命令第3部队
to hand over Kaiju No. 8 straight away.
立即将怪兽8号移交本部
Kaiju No. 8's vitals have stabilized. No signs of transformation.
怪兽8号的生命体征稳定 没有变身的征兆
It's really him?
真的是他吗？
It's been about 24 hours.
已经过了整整一天吗？
What's going to happen to me now?
接下来我会怎么样呢？
Kaiju that are strong enough to be assigned a number
而且冠上代号的强力怪兽
are used as parts for a special weapon after they're taken down.
在被打倒后，通常都会 用来当作特殊武器的零件
Worst case scenario, that'll happen to you.
最糟的情况，你也会如此
After getting one step closer to fighting by her side!
本来以为终于更靠近她身边一步了
Mina must be pissed at me.
米娜一定很生气吧
It's time.
时间到了
We will be transferring you to headquarters now.
现在开始将你移送至本部的设施
Mi…
米…
-Vice-Captain! I'm sorry, I-- -Don't talk.
-副队长！抱歉，我… -别说话
Stand up.
站起来
Of course, they're pissed.
也对
I kept this big secret from them.
毕竟我隐瞒了很不得了的秘密
The security troops accompanying you are all ready.
负责同行的警备部队已准备完毕
Shit. I can't look him in the face.
糟糕，我不敢看他的脸
He was always worried about me.
他总是一直担心我
I'm certain he can't forgive me.
肯定没办法原谅我吧
I'm sorry.
对不起
-Now, it's really over. -Senpai!
-这次真的到此… -前辈！
I know you'll be back. I believe it.
我相信你会回来的
Ichikawa.
市川
That Ichikawa. He'll be getting 50 pushups for talking without permission.
市川那家伙，未经许可私下交谈 得罚五十下俯卧撑
Mina?
米娜？
We're not under any surveillance here.
这里就没有监视的眼目了
When you ran over to save everyone without hesitation,
你毫不犹豫地冲出去拯救大家的时候
your kaiju form surprised me, but I also thought,
我对你的怪兽型态感到惊讶 同时也在想：
"This is the Kafka-kun I know."
“真像卡夫卡的作风”
We're collecting witness accounts and footage to help you right now.
我们正在搜集对你有利的证词和视频
If we can prove that you're human,
只要能证明你是人类
we might be able to avoid extermination.
也许就能避免被处分
Your performance as an officer will be included in the report.
我也打算将你作为 队员的表现一起报告上去
There's no one in the Third Division who thinks
第3部队里没有一个人认为
that you're an enemy.
你是怪兽
It's time.
时间到
Sit down.
坐下
Kafka Hibino. According to Regulation 13 of the Defense Force,
日比野卡夫卡 根据防卫队规则第13条
you will be transferred to the Ariake Rinkai Base.
现在要将你移送到有明临海基地
-If civilians are put at risk-- -Mina.
-若路上危及市民… -米娜
Can I still
我还能…
keep working towards fighting by your side?
以你的身边为目标吗？
Yeah. I'll wait for you.
嗯，我会一直等你
That idiot.
那个白痴
Third Division, salute!
第3部队，敬礼！
What is this, Vice-Captain Hoshina?
保科副队长，这是做什么？
We are saluting our superior, Captain Ashiro.
这是向长官亚白米娜队长致敬
Of course, you are. You must never salute a kaiju.
也对，你们是不可能向怪兽敬礼的
Yes, sir.
是
DEFENSE FORCE RINKAI BASE
（防卫队有明临海基地）
Barrier Number 31, this is Number 23.
第23至第31闸门
Lock is functioning properly.
确认锁定功能正常
Kaiju No. 8 has been restrained.
怪兽8号，拘束完毕
FEW DAYS LATER
（几天后）
I still can't believe it.
我到现在还是不敢相信
I never thought Old Man was Kaiju No. 8!
没想到大叔就是怪兽8号
That squishy-bellied old man!
毕竟是那个软绵绵肚子的大叔啊
Right, Reno?
对吧，雷诺？
Hibino-san
日比野
saved me from a kaiju.
从怪兽眼前救了我
He would always find kaiju's weak spots
他总是能找到怪物的弱点
and was always cheerful during training, too.
而且在训练时总是很开朗
Yeah, I know. Old Man helped me too.
说起来我也是，大叔也救了我
It's not for us to decide.
下决定的不是我们
It's the Neutralization Bureau.
是讨伐厅
As expected from a former SDF officer. It's a system of hierarchy, huh?
果然是前自卫队军官 上情下达是理所当然的，对吧？
But that's how it is.
但也很合理
It's a serious thing for a human to turn into a kaiju.
人类变成怪兽的事情可不是小事
If this gets out to the public,
如果这个事实公布出来
the whole world will go into a panic.
全世界都会陷入恐慌
We'll live our lives constantly afraid that the person next to us
人们会开始怀疑邻居有可能是怪兽
could be a kaiju.
从此在恐惧中度日吧
No.
怎么会…
The issue is bigger
这已经不是
than anything we ever have influence over.
我们能插嘴的问题了
Senpai.
前辈…
Come in.
进来吧
Excuse me.
失礼了
Did you call for me?
您叫我吗？
Can you put those reports together? I'm in a bit of a rush.
请把这些整理一下，有点紧急
Yes, ma'am. This is…
遵命，这个…
-Can I count on you? -Yes, ma'am.
-能拜托你吗？ -是，当然可以
Vice-Captain!
副队长
We've finished removing all of the scrapped cars.
废车辆已经清除完毕
Thanks. Good work.
哦，辛苦了
What do you think will happen to Hibino?
日比野会怎么样呢？
He's got to come back.
他不回来的话，我会伤脑筋的
You know, when he fought me, he went easy on me.
那家伙和我战斗时手下留情了
Treating me like I'm weak or something.
真是瞧不起人
I agree, sir.
是，没错
Next time, he's fighting me with all he's got.
下次要让他拿出全力来
DIRECTOR GENERAL'S OFFICE
（长官室）
Come in.
进来吧
What is it?
什么事？
Director General Shinomiya.
四之宫长官
I'm here to request Kafka Hibino's extermination to be canceled.
我是来请求撤回 对日比野卡夫卡的处分
He's saved my life as well.
我也曾被他救了一命
-Please have mercy on him…. -You fool.
-请长官从宽处置… -愚蠢的家伙
You've come to talk about this stupid failure?
你来就为了讲这种无聊丢脸的话吗？
But…
但是…
Look at this.
看看这个吧
Yes, sir.
是
This is an X-ray scan of his chest.
这是他的胸部X光片
The thing on his left chest.
在左胸腔内
It looks very similar to a heart, but it's a core.
有着像心脏一样的东西，是核心
No.
怎么会…
He's not human.
他并不是人类
He's a kaiju.
他是怪兽
Just like the kaiju that killed your mother.
就是杀死你母亲的怪兽
You heard me. Now get out.
听懂的话就出去
Dad.
爸爸
Even so, I want to believe in him.
即使如此，我还是想相信他
Another physical exam? How long are we going to do this?
又是身体检查吗？ 要弄到什么时候啊？
I'd love to sleep in a real bed soon.
我想上床睡觉了呢
I know you'll be back. I believe it.
我相信你会回来的
I have
我…
a lot of things I need to say to everybody.
还有很多话想对大家说
I'll never give up.
我不能放弃
I need to go back to that place
我要再一次…
one more time.
回到那里
We're being transferred?
要调到其他部队？
It's just a temporary measure.
这只是临时的处置
Due to the recent kaiju attacks,
由于这次怪兽造成的灾害
the Tachikawa Base has lost 75% of its function.
立川基地失去了75%的功能
It was decided that it cannot function as a facility to train new officers.
因此上级判断 无法再作为新人培训机关
We've had No. 9 and No. 10 appear one after another.
继9号之后 这次的10号和大怪兽的连续出现
Higher ups are worried about what this might mean.
让上级对这种情势有种怀疑
They think it could be a series of Swarm Disasters.
这或许是一系列群发型大灾害
So, we're going to keep getting more of these attacks?
那种东西还会继续出现吗？
Not only that. Multiple attacks could happen simultaneously.
不只如此，还可能同时在多处发生
We have to be prepared.
我们必须做好准备
The key is you all.
而你们就是关键
We'll be training the exceptionally talented new officers
我们要跨越部队的藩篱
across Division borders.
培养全部队的优秀新人
-That's why we're being transferred? -You hear that? We're exceptional!
-所以才将我们调走？ -因为很优秀啊
Is it because of No. 8?
是因为8号吗？
What do you mean?
什么意思？
Could our superiors be planning to split up the officers
不是因为上级要将与 日比野卡夫卡友好的队员打散
who were the closest to Kafka Hibino to monitor us?
好方便监视的关系吗？
Captain Ashiro.
亚白队长
-If that's the case, then I won't follow. -Wait.
-如果是那样，我才不接受… -等等
It's beautiful that you care about your fellow officer this way.
你们对于同期队员的感情很难得
But this plan had been in the works for a long time.
但这个计划早就已经列入考虑
It has nothing to do with Kafka Hibino.
和日比野卡夫卡没有关系
I understand.
我了解了
But to be transferred to another division so suddenly…
但忽然说要调到其他部队也太突然
That's right. I joined because I looked up to the Third Division.
对啊，我是因为崇拜第3部队…
To you!
崇拜您才来的！
I'll do it.
我接受
Did you hear what she said? We're getting split up!
你有听懂吗？我们要分散各处了耶！
-You should think before answering. -I'll do it.
-多用点脑思考再回答吧 -我接受
DAD
（父亲）
Yes.
对，就是这样
It's about inside the Defense Force, so I can't speak on the details.
这是防卫队内部的事情 所以不能讲得太详细
But there's a man I really want to save.
但有一位我们 无论如何都想帮助的男人
Yes. I know it's near impossible.
是，我知道可能性很低
Thank you, sir.
麻烦您了
Sorry. I didn't mean to eavesdrop.
抱歉，我找不到好时机搭话
I came up here on my own. Don't worry about it.
我自己上来的，别在意
Aoi.
葵
I was talking to my former superior in the SDF.
我打电话给我原本的自卫队上司
I asked him to connect me to someone who could influence Kafka's punishment.
我请他帮忙联系重要人士 看能不能对卡夫卡处分说两句话
I didn't expect you
真意外
to go around making personal requests like that.
没想到你会因为私事去拜托别人
I told you, didn't I? I don't want to lose anyone.
我说过了吧？我不想失去任何人
Kafka Hibino is a member of the Third Division,
日比野卡夫卡是我们第3部队的伙伴
isn't he?
不是吗？
I…
我…
If we can prove that you're human, we might be able to avoid extermination.
只要能证明你是人类 也许就能避免被处分
Just like Mina said.
米娜说的没错
I'll prove that I'm human, and I'll go back to the Third Division.
我要证明我是人类，回到大家的身边
First, I have to make them listen to me.
首先得让他们听我说话
Director General Shinomiya?
四之宫长官？
I didn't think the Director General would go himself.
没想到长官会亲自出马
The more important something is, the more he wants to deal with it himself.
越是重要的事情，他就越要亲力亲为
That's the kind of man he is.
他就是这种男人
Director General!
长官！
I'm not a kaiju!
我不是怪兽！
Release his restraints.
解除拘束
But that man is Kaiju No. 8. It's too risky!
但他是怪兽8号，这样太危险了
Who do you think you're talking to?
你是在和谁说话？
If he's really Daikaiju class,
如果他真的是大怪兽级
he'd be able to break these easily.
轻而易举就能破坏这些东西
If he's sitting there without resisting, he's doing so at his will.
他会老实坐在那里 只是出于他的意愿
Maybe this man would listen to me.
如果是这个人，或许会愿意听我说话
Director General Shinomiya. I'm a human.
四之宫长官，我是人类…
Kafka Hibino!
日比野卡夫卡！
What was that?
突然攻击是做什么？
Let me tell you something.
告诉你一件事吧
If a creature can block a bullet with his bare skin,
能用肉身挡住子弹的生物
in this world, we don't call those humans,
在这世界上可不叫做人类
Kaiju No. 8.
怪兽8号
Dad.
爸爸
I'm not Kaiju No. 8.
我不叫怪兽8号
I'm Kafka Hibino.
我是日比野卡夫卡
I see.
是吗？
That's the sign.
是信号
FS-1002 has been unlocked. Permission to use has been granted.
FS-1002解除锁定 同意使用申请
What is that?
那是什么？
Nerve link is clear.
神经连结完成
The driver and syncing with Kaiju No. 2 cells, all clear.
操纵者与怪兽2号 细胞同步全部完成
FS-1002 start-up is complete.
FS-1002启动完毕
In that case, die in that form.
那么，你就用那副模样死去吧
We'll begin with the extermination of Kaiju No. 8.
现在开始处理怪兽8号
I won't transform all the way. I'll prove that I'm human.
我不能完全变身 我一定要证明我是人类
Kafka!
卡夫卡！
He hasn't changed.
真是宝刀未老
The man
真不愧是
who was once called the strongest in Defense Force history.
被誉为防卫队史上最强的男人
You're looking more like a kaiju now.
变得很像是怪兽了啊
I can't take that attack directly. I have to keep dodging him
被直击就惨了，只好努力躲开攻击
until he's at his drive limit!
等他达到驱动界限了
Why is my body reacting this way?
这副身体怎么会有这种反应？
It's the same feeling I felt when I faced a Daikaiju.
这和对上大怪兽时的感觉一样
But who I'm facing right now is…
但对手是…
Could it be, I'm sensing a Daikaiju from the Director General?
难道是从长官身上 传来大怪兽的气息？
Kaiju No. 2.
怪兽2号
A kaiju that almost drove Sapporo to total annihilation back in 1972.
1972年差点毁灭整座札幌市
It's the second kaiju to be assigned a designated number.
是被指定识别编号的第二个个体
He was a Daikaiju with an immense destructive force
具备惊人的破坏力
and so much pride that he did not give up until his very last breath.
以及高傲的性格 临死也不屈服的大怪兽
We made a suit and arm based on No. 2.
以2号为基础制造的战斗服和拳套
And the only man who could wear that was your father,
世界上唯一能运用这套装备的 就是你的父亲
Isao Shinomiya.
四之宫功
So, this is what Kikoru was talking about!
原来如此，这就是琪歌露说过的
The Identified Kaiju Weapons, Numbers!
识别怪兽兵器！
No. I can't take these attacks any more.
不行，没办法再承受伤害了
Dodge them!
要躲开！
What? I can't move!
咦？动不了，为什么？
When did that happen?
什么时候？
Shit.
可恶
Kafka Hibino!
日比野卡夫卡！
Thank God.
太好了
I finally meet you in your true form, kaiju.
终于露出真面目了，怪兽
Huh? Something's wrong.
怎么回事？他的样子…
I knew it. Something weird is happening.
果然，有哪里不对劲
What's going on? My body's not listening to me.
这是怎么回事？身体不听使唤
Shit. I'm trying to prove to them that I'm human,
可恶，别说要证明自己是人类了
but I'm becoming more and more like a kaiju.
这个模样根本就是怪兽啊
Kill…
杀…
Kill all kaiju. Kill…
杀死…怪兽…
Stop it! You're human, Kafka Hibino!
快住手！ 你是人类吧，日比野卡夫卡！
Subtitle translation by: Yukimi Ohashi
字幕翻译：唐咏杰